<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Shriman Keshri</title><link>https://shrimansoft.github.io/knowledge-base/</link><description>Recent content on Shriman Keshri</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://shrimansoft.github.io/knowledge-base/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Why Neural network</title><link>https://shrimansoft.github.io/knowledge-base/pages/why-neural-network/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shrimansoft.github.io/knowledge-base/pages/why-neural-network/</guid><description>Hello, everyone. I recently gave a talk on neural networks at the NISER Coding Club. The address was intended for a general audience. So, we have yet to use any technical jargon. In this post, I will convey the same here, But before I begin I like to point out that this bog has some exercise that is degined to make you absrobe the matarial for its fullest. So, if you are reading to Get the Real</description></item><item><title>Big realizations</title><link>https://shrimansoft.github.io/knowledge-base/pages/big-realizations/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shrimansoft.github.io/knowledge-base/pages/big-realizations/</guid><description>These are the list of big realisations I have experienced. Idea of separation is an illusion.
Time is an illusion. ( there is no time there is only Unfolding )
We are not an exception to this nature. We are an example.
The force of feeling and how we can avoid this by practicing Vespasian.
( not yet realized ) The world is dynamic. ( Becoming otherwise)
( not yet realized ) Why do we exist?</description></item><item><title>Circle of time</title><link>https://shrimansoft.github.io/knowledge-base/pages/circle-of-time/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shrimansoft.github.io/knowledge-base/pages/circle-of-time/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Generalisation of reinforcement learning</title><link>https://shrimansoft.github.io/knowledge-base/pages/generalisation-of-reinforcement-learning/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shrimansoft.github.io/knowledge-base/pages/generalisation-of-reinforcement-learning/</guid><description>What do we mean my generalization?
By the Process and Reality &amp;ldquo;we are no exception to this nature we are example of it&amp;rdquo;. Taking this Idea we can say that everything is like us has some level of active participation in the nature and during this interaction these things are evolving too.
To make this some what abstract Idea that every thing are like us evolving. I like to generalise this Idea that there is an agent rather every thing is an agent.</description></item><item><title>Important ideas</title><link>https://shrimansoft.github.io/knowledge-base/pages/important-ideas/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shrimansoft.github.io/knowledge-base/pages/important-ideas/</guid><description>Reinforcement Learning
Consciousness
Modularity
Causal inference
Evolution
Ability to use tool
Language ( giving identity to our feelings)
randomness
sub-representation
Reprasentation
learning
Images of Important Ideas tools
RL
randomness
Exact sequence
attention
action = observation
Circle of time.
World view
Different feeling
Randomness/ Predictability.
Time
Space
Separation/ Identity
Intelligence/ consciousness.
Drive ( unmoved mover)
Creativity.
Free will
How log is this present?
How past -&amp;gt; future?
where is action action min comes from?</description></item><item><title>Markove decision process</title><link>https://shrimansoft.github.io/knowledge-base/pages/markove-decision-process/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shrimansoft.github.io/knowledge-base/pages/markove-decision-process/</guid><description>id:: 6480345f-4734-4296-ab89-5203b50f3c33 RL interaction Dynamics Markove decision process is a mathematical model.
When we fix the policy, the above process becomes automatic. It will just run and run.
Because of a lack of knowledge, we use probability in this. #randomness
The above interaction dynamics can be studied using the MDP. So here the MDP comes in picture.
The MDP is how the agent sees his interaction with the world.
Let me elaborate on this and give a picture of where this idea will fit in the scheme of World view.</description></item><item><title>Modularity</title><link>https://shrimansoft.github.io/knowledge-base/pages/modularity/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shrimansoft.github.io/knowledge-base/pages/modularity/</guid><description>Thought The complexity of the system increases when we go from atoms to Organism.
We can understand And Realise Some of the above structures of the system to predict what will going happen to the system. #sub-representation #randomness
That is good, but why is there modularity in nature itself?
what is the reason? why does one world want to control another world why why?
We can say something exists that&amp;rsquo;s why it exists.</description></item><item><title>Reinforcement Learning</title><link>https://shrimansoft.github.io/knowledge-base/pages/reinforcement-learning/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shrimansoft.github.io/knowledge-base/pages/reinforcement-learning/</guid><description>Reinforcement learning, on the other hand, is a type of machine learning that involves an agent learning from its environment through trial and error. The agent receives feedback in the form of rewards or punishments for its actions, and over time, it learns to choose actions that maximize its reward. Supervised Learning: Learning with labels defined by human Unsupervised Learning: finding patterns in data. Reinforcement Learning: This is a $4^{rd}$ machine learning paradigm, in which agent tries to maximise its reward signal.</description></item><item><title>Unfolding</title><link>https://shrimansoft.github.io/knowledge-base/pages/unfolding/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shrimansoft.github.io/knowledge-base/pages/unfolding/</guid><description>What I mean when I say unfolding. It&amp;rsquo;s like something was folded before, and now we are unfolding it. So, what do we mean? I like to talk about this thing with examples of this unfolding.
Example 1 DNA $\to$ organism.
Example 2 Everything in this nature is unfolding. Time is it self a manifestation of this unfolding.
Example 3 future $\to$ present $\to$ past ( this is coming from Process and Reality ) #Circle of time</description></item><item><title>Idea of separation</title><link>https://shrimansoft.github.io/knowledge-base/pages/idea-of-separation/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shrimansoft.github.io/knowledge-base/pages/idea-of-separation/</guid><description>Before I talk about the Triangular MDP, let me first discuss the idea of separation. Why am I talking about this? Because there are two challenges we have with Triangular MDP. One is how it works if it is already there, and the other is how it can come into being from thin air.
I will try to answer the first one on the page of Triangular MDP, but to address the second question, we need to look at how humans get the idea of separation.</description></item><item><title>Jul 21st, 2023</title><link>https://shrimansoft.github.io/knowledge-base/pages/jul-21st-2023/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shrimansoft.github.io/knowledge-base/pages/jul-21st-2023/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>