<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Idea on Shriman Keshri</title><link>https://shrimansoft.github.io/knowledge-base/categories/idea/</link><description>Recent content in Idea on Shriman Keshri</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://shrimansoft.github.io/knowledge-base/categories/idea/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>4 causes</title><link>https://shrimansoft.github.io/knowledge-base/pages/4-causes/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shrimansoft.github.io/knowledge-base/pages/4-causes/</guid><description>{{video https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zdEzyA2HGnY}}
Material Cause: The matter that makes up an object, like the chemical composition of an apple. Formal Cause: The unique form or structure that defines the object&amp;rsquo;s identity. Efficient Cause: The process or event that brings an object into existence, such as the growth of the apple tree. Final Cause: The ultimate purpose or potential of an object, like the apple&amp;rsquo;s potential to grow into an apple tree. 🌱 Potency and Actuality: Objects have potency (potential) and actuality (realized potential).</description></item><item><title>cling to</title><link>https://shrimansoft.github.io/knowledge-base/pages/cling-to/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shrimansoft.github.io/knowledge-base/pages/cling-to/</guid><description>Aug 4th, 2023 you don&amp;rsquo;t cling to person or places. you cling to the experience you have with them.
and since the experience is dynamic in nature how can you cling to it.
so, you cling to the memory of those experience and the effort and force we appy to recreate those experience is worth less and not going to work.
our lack of wisdom make us do so.
and the frustatoin of not geting any result make us misarable.</description></item><item><title>One direction Communication</title><link>https://shrimansoft.github.io/knowledge-base/pages/one-direction-communication/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shrimansoft.github.io/knowledge-base/pages/one-direction-communication/</guid><description>File storage : communication from past to future. #Memory
In Space: we can do both direction communication .
But in Time we can only do one direction communication.
I was listening to an audiobook (1984 by George Orwell). In that book, The character wanted to write a letter. but he doesn&amp;rsquo;t have anyone to send this letter,
To whom I am going to write this latter. My Future.
but he wondered how could he communicate with his future.</description></item><item><title>randomness</title><link>https://shrimansoft.github.io/knowledge-base/pages/randomness/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shrimansoft.github.io/knowledge-base/pages/randomness/</guid><description>Why do Turing machine with a coin is capable of something more? Why do Nature follow some law ( constraints) and why something are random ( free at least from the Ability of our thought)?
Randomness $\to$ Evolution $\to$ RL I was wondering from where this randomness comes. If we understand from where this randomness comes, we will know the source of the origin of Evolution. We will get the origin of learning in RL.</description></item><item><title>World view</title><link>https://shrimansoft.github.io/knowledge-base/pages/world-view/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shrimansoft.github.io/knowledge-base/pages/world-view/</guid><description>This comes from the fact that we can think inside our head that is just like another world.
Important ideas Transfer flexibility/ability to use new tools. These two ideas were very similar.
Agent is doing something from his hand but now if I will give him some proper tool in his hand it is like changing the environment. Now learning to use the tool is similar to adopting to new environment.</description></item></channel></rss>